

# Philani Thulani Ngwenya

**CURRENT JOB** 

IT Helpdesk Agent UCS

2nd Floor 34 Melrose Boulevard, Melrose Arch, Melrose Johannesburg, GP 2196

South Africa

h: 0333993625 m: 0724499806 f: 0865150095

w: 0878204617

philani.ngwenya97@gmail.com

http://za.linkedin.com/pub/philani-ngwenya/20/490/ab3

# **Summary**

Professional help-desk consultant in Information & Technology with 4 years of experience working as a helpdesk consultant, using Remedy-call logging system and also Simplicity for resolving incidents logged by help-desk.withing the 4 years i have learnt the importance of customer service ,Investigating reasons for problems and solving them for clients,troubleshoot and establish hardware issues. As much as I have worked in the support desk, I am eager ,willing to learn and grow even in a different environment from that I've been in. I would like to be given a chance in the following fields Junior Tester, Front-End Web designer, IT Desktop Support or IT-Administrator

## References

# Seshni Govender (Superior)

Team Leader Business Connexion 084 4006 318 SeshniG@mdd.co.za

My team leader at BCX

#### Francis Lawrence

(Superior)

Support Engineer Argility 073 544 8084 flawrence@argility.com My former team leader at ucs

# Thokozani Shandu (Peer)

Former Manager at woolworths McMillan 071 7913 009

former manager and a friend from woolworths

# **Objectives**

- Seeking a position as an it-administrator / front-end-web developer / junior desktop technician in initiatives that utilize state-of-the-art, software and/or hardware components with a creative, technology-driven organization in an environment that encourages innovative thinking, recognition, and career development.
- To continue my career with an organization that will utilize my helpdesk support and web design skills to benefit mutual growth and success.

# **Interests**

- · computer games
- travelling
- · listening to music and also watch movies

#### Skills

# Remote Support (Advanced)

· Problem solving abilities

<1 Years Experience, (Currently in use)

- - · Good communication skills, verbal and written
  - Ability to work under pressure
  - · Team Player



- · Ability to Self-Manage and Self-Motivated
- · Positive attitude
- · Customer Focus
- · Listening skills
- · Adaptability Building customer loyalty

### Linux (Beginner)

1-2 Years Experience, (Currently in use)

Use it to run basic commands together with SQL 2008 to manipulate date from a live database

#### Databases (Beginner)



<1 Years Experience, (Last Used <1 year ago)

I am knowledgeable in SQL Server, Oracle 10g, and MS Access. I can provide the following services in the above mentioned databases:

Analysis, Design, Development, and Maintenance

## Web Development (Beginner)



<1 Years Experience, (Last Used <1 year ago)

My advance web development capabilities encampuses analysis, design, development, and maintenance work using the following languages:

Java Script, VB Script, and HTML,/XHTML

# **Work History**

## **UCS-TS**

Johannesburg, GP, South Africa

Sep 2010 - Present

#### **Helpdesk Agent**

## **Duties and Responsibilities**

Responsible for the following focus areas:

- Ensure the phone is always answered timeously and in a professional manner
- Display professional, helpful, responsive behavior and willingness to assist the users at all times
- · Ensure no telephone calls are dropped
- Responsible for taking ownership of all incidents that are specifically logged and therefore, are required to manage the incident during the incident lifecycle
- Ensure that all IT incidents are logged, without exception
- Logging of incidents:- Record details of all incidents, timeously and accurately paying particular attention what the actual issue or request is
- Ensure that the data captured is of a high quality to facilitate trending and analysis of all incidents
- Demonstrate effective and efficient management of incidents during the life cycle of the incident using Simplicity

#### Respond to all raised incidents via:

- · Telephone calls (ensure that the telephone script is followed)
- · Emails
- · Every other channel available
- If unsuccessful, reassign and/or escalate the incident to 2nd/3rd level support, including the Field Service Engineer

- Responsible for checking the Service Desk Voice Messaging system for User calls.— Must call the user back to obtain incident details
- · Must assign the incident and ensure incident resolution process begins
- Track and update incidents via the simplicity system
- Responsible for checking the Service Desk Email Messaging system for User calls.
- · Responsible for escalation for P1 incidents via Voice comms, email, SMS etc.
- · Take ownership if any incident that have been re-assigned to you
- Hand-over all incident to the next shift for further resolution. Responsible for escalation of incidents to IT internal management or to external 3rd Party Management if required to resolve and restore the Service affected
- Responsible for providing the user with regular feedback on the progress of the incident
- Responsible for ensuring that incidents within Simplicity record the activities taken during the incident life cycle to reach a resolutionMonitoring of incidents
- Responsible for ensuring that all details captured into Simplicity system are accurate, error free and clearly highlights what the impact is / was to the user
- Responsible for following up of all reassignments to ensure that incidents do not breach and that adequate / timeous progress is being made as per agreed SLA's
- Monitor the progress of all incidents assigned and ensure that all steps are taken by the right resource resolve the incident before it breaches

### Closing of incidents

- Once a resolution has been found and/ implemented take responsibility for obtaining permission via email from the user to close the incident logged.
- The incident may not be closed unless the user has given permission to close it.
- Responsible for attaching required permission email to the logged incident within Simplicty ensure that resolution details are filled in appropriately.
- Follow-up with the user on the resolution of the incident. Governance and Compliance
- Ensure adherence to all ACSA policies, process, standards and proceduresEnsure compliance to IT security standards and best practice

### **Audit**

- · Action audit report findings.
- Implement developed systems, timeously, for the Service Desk environment e.g.; trouble shooting guides, methodologies, operation manuals etc.

#### **Customer Service**

#### Learning

- Respond timeously to customer queries and provide regular feedbackUpdate customers on the progress being made with their specific incident. Actively find ways to improve customer service Provide customer service as per agreed SLA's with Business.
- · Performance Contracts
- Participate in annual contracting process, agree and sign required documentationParticipate in quarterly performance management process / reviewsSkills Development
- Ensure learning solutions are identified, proposed and implemented according to ongoing personal and team development plans. Negotiate training and development requirements with manager.

### **Business Connexion**

Durban, ZN, South Africa

Mar 2008 - Aug 2010

#### Helpdesk

#### Duties

- Act as the first point of contact (telephonic) for the user community of IT services.
- Log each incident on Remedy

- Provide contact level support and keep track of the Remedy incidents that have been assigned to second and third level support groups.
- Keep the user informed about the status and the progress made on the incident reported by the user.
- Attempt telephonic 1st level diagnostic in order to quickly resolve / restore the failed serviceAct as the single point of contact (SPoC) for all IT related issues,incidents, servicerequest etc for the user community

#### Key Responsibilities

- Telephonically supporting users nationally using the remedy call logging system.
- Logging and assigning, updating and closing of all Remedy Incidents.
- Doing first-line support, taking preventative action and implementing workarounds when needed.
- Following and escalating problems incidents with other departments during the day-today operations
- Updating remedy with meaningful quality information and giving regular feedback regarding incidents or procedural changes.
- · Offering a professional service to internal and external customer
- Abiding by the rules, guidelines and policies as stipulated

## **Education**

## Durban University of Technology (DUT)

Durban, ZN, South Africa

Feb 2004 - Jun 2008

### N Dip:IT, Information Technology

## **Major subjects**

- · Development software
- · Information Systems

#### **Programming Languages**

- C# (Software Development)
- Java (Technical Programming)
- Visual Basic 6.0(Development Software)

#### Web Page Design

Internet Programming(HTML, CSS,SQL,JavaScript,XML)

#### Other subjects

- · Systems Software (Networks and Operating Systems theory)
- · Communication Skills
- · Accounting Skills
- · Legal Aspects

This next-generation resume was created using VisualCV

